<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<?asciidoc-toc?>
<?asciidoc-numbered?>

<article lang="en">
<articleinfo>
    <date>2023-08-29</date>
</articleinfo>
<simpara>Spring Boot offers a fast way to build applications. It looks at your classpath and at the
beans you have configured, makes reasonable assumptions about what you are missing, and
adds those items. With Spring Boot, you can focus more on business features and less on
infrastructure.</simpara>
<simpara>The following examples show what Spring Boot can do for you:</simpara>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Is Spring MVC on the classpath? There are several specific beans you almost always need,
and Spring Boot adds them automatically. A Spring MVC application also needs a servlet
container, so Spring Boot automatically configures embedded Tomcat.
</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Is Jetty on the classpath? If so, you probably do NOT want Tomcat but instead want
embedded Jetty. Spring Boot handles that for you.
</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>
Is Thymeleaf on the classpath? If so, there are a few beans that must always be added to
your application context. Spring Boot adds them for you.
</simpara>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<simpara>These are just a few examples of the automatic configuration Spring Boot provides. At the
same time, Spring Boot does not get in your way. For example, if Thymeleaf is on your
path, Spring Boot automatically adds a <literal>SpringTemplateEngine</literal> to your application context.
But if you define your own <literal>SpringTemplateEngine</literal> with your own settings, Spring Boot does
not add one. This leaves you in control with little effort on your part.</simpara>
<note><simpara>Spring Boot does not generate code or make edits to your files. Instead, when you
start your application, Spring Boot dynamically wires up beans and settings and applies
them to your application context.</simpara></note>
</article>
